Guide to the John Leggett Writings
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
John Leggett writings
1960-1969
YCAL MSS 486
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.13
(8 boxes)
The John Leggett writings contain drafts and proofs for Leggett's first three novels, Wilder Stone (1960), The Gloucester Branch (1964), and Who Took the Gold Away (1969).
Leggett, John, 1917-2015
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John Leggett, 1960 to 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
John Leggett Papers, MsC 503, Special Collections Department, University of Iowa.
John Leggett (1917-)
John Leggett was born November 11, 1917, in New York, N.Y. to Bleecker Noel and Dorothy (Mahar) Leggett. Leggett attended Andover, received an A.B. from Yale University in 1942, and served in the U.S. Naval Reserve from 1942 to 1945. He married Mary Lee Fahnestock in 1948, with whom he had three children. They divorced in 1986, and Leggett married Edwina Bennington of San Francisco.
Leggett was an editor and publicity director for Houghton Mifflin Company in Boston from 1950 to 1960 and an editor at Harper & Row Publishing in New York from 1960 to 1967. In 1969 Leggett became a professor of English and the director of the Writers' Workshop at the University of Iowa, Iowa City, serving in those capacities until 1987.
Leggett's published writings include Wilder Stone (1960), The Gloucester Branch (1964), Who Took the Gold Away (1969), Ross and Tom: Two American Tragedies (1974), and Gulliver House (1979).
Biographical information taken from John Leggett Papers, MsC 503, Special Collections Department, University of Iowa.
Scope and Contents
The John Leggett writings contain drafts and proofs for Leggett's first three novels, Wilder Stone, The Gloucester Branch, and Who Took the Gold Away, published from 1960 to 1969.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by title.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Leggett, John, 1917-2015
- The Gloucester Branch, notes, drafts, and galley proof, 1964, undated; 6 (Box 1)
- The Gloucester Branch, page proof, 1964 (Box 2)
- Wilder Stone, setting copy, 1960 (Box 2)
- Who Took the Gold Away?, notes and drafts, 1968-1969; 6 (Box 3)
- Who Took the Gold Away?, original draft, undated; 5 (Box 4)
- Who Took the Gold Away?, setting copy, typescript and photocopy, undated; 5 (Box 5)
- Who Took the Gold Away?, setting copy, undated (Box 6)
- Who Took the Gold Away?, galley proof, 1969 January 7 (Box 6)
- Who Took the Gold Away?, page proofs, 1969 February 21; 2 (Box 7)
- Who Took the Gold Away?, plate proof, 1969 (Box 8)